http://www.canfor.com/privacy-policy

Website Privacy Policy Scope This is a statement of the privacy practices applicable to Canfor Corporation (“Canfor”), its subsidiaries and describes how we collect, use and disclose personal information of our customers, website users and other individuals on our website. In this statement references to “Canfor”, “we” and “our” and similar references may include—or refer only to—Canfor or one or more subsidiaries, including without limitation, Canadian Forest Products Ltd.,
and Canfor Wood Products Marketing Ltd., Canfor Southern Pine, Inc., Canfor Pulp Products Inc. and Canfor Pulp Ltd., as applicable. Personal Information Personal information is any information about an identifiable individual or that permits an individual to be identified such as your personal contact information (e.g. name, postal address, telephone number and e-mail) and your IP address but does not include business contact information or other non-personal information such as the type of browser you are using or the referring URL. Our Commitment Canfor is committed to protecting the privacy and security of the personal information of individuals with whom we interact in accordance with applicable privacy legislation. Respecting and protecting your privacy is important to us and a priority in our continuing relationship. We have developed this policy to set out our practices for the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information.
Consent We collect, use and disclose your personal information with your consent (which may be express or implied) or as required or permitted by law. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of that personal information in accordance with this statement of privacy practices. If this statement of privacy practices is not acceptable to you, please do not submit any of your personal information. Subject to legal and contractual requirements and upon reasonable notice, you may withdraw your consent to our further collection, use and disclosure of your personal information, including by requesting that your name be removed from our telephone, mail or email marketing lists, by contacting us at the email address provided below. If you refuse or withdraw consent, we may be unable to provide you with certain services or information, but we will not require personal information beyond what is required to provide those services or information. Nature of Collection We collect personal information directly from you or from interactions with you. The personal information we collect may include information relevant to our providing of services or information to you or in the case of hiring and employment, to evaluate you for available positions. We limit the personal information we collect and use to that which is necessary to fulfill the purposes identified in the next section below.
Except as set out in this statement of privacy practices, we will not collect, sell, distribute or use personal information for any other purposes without your further consent, as required by law or as authorized by applicable privacy legislation. Our Purposes for Collection and Use Canfor collects and uses your personal information so that we can carry out one or more of the following:
administer and fulfill your specific request for information; allow us to communicate with you and authenticate your identity; provide support to assist you with your questions or complaints; detect and protect against fraud or error; administer community-based donation/sponsorship programs; administer the job hiring application database and program; and evaluate applicants for existing or future employment opportunities with Canfor.
If we need your personal information for any other purpose, we will identify that purpose and obtain your consent. Storing and Sharing of Personal Information Canfor takes great care to ensure your personal information is securely stored. Your personal information is held in confidence by Canfor. Access to this information is restricted to authorized personnel of Canfor and, unless otherwise required or permitted by law, will only be disclosed to third-party service providers responsible for administering our database or programs or providing Canfor with services, provided that such service providers use the information only for the purposes for which it was disclosed, and agree to maintain privacy policies consistent with those of Canfor. Personal information collected by Canfor may be used, processed and stored outside of Canada and may be subject to disclosure in accordance with the laws of such foreign jurisdictions. The personal information that you disclose on an employment application will only be used to complete the necessary employment-related evaluation and will not be used for marketing or other purposes, unless we ask for and receive your consent for such use(s). Our Websites We use various technologies to collect non-personal information about your use of our websites. In particular, we use:
cookies (small files placed on your browser by us or our service
providers that facilitate recognition of your browser to allow for storage of
user preferences and related information); pixel tags (invisible images placed on certain pages of our websites for
the purpose of tracking activity on websites); and automatic logging of session data (information automatically collected
by our servers such as Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, return
visits, referring pages and transaction information).
These technologies allow us to:
enhance the functionality of our websites (e.g. user I.D. and password
prompts); obtain statistical analysis of website traffic (e.g. what pages are most
popular); administer our websites and servers; and enhance user experience on our websites and improve our services.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies.
If you reject our cookies, or the cookies of service providers placed on our behalf, we cannot gather the information about your visit to our websites that we use these cookies to provide and by doing so this may affect your use of our websites and your ability to access certain features of the website or engage in transactions or upload information through our websites. If you fill out a form on our websites, we may link, for the purposes described above, the browsing information associated with the cookies placed by or for us on your browser with your other personal information in our control. For more information regarding our use of cookies, pixel tags or session logging, or our use of service providers and their technologies in connection with our websites as it relates to your personal information, please email our Privacy Officer at the e-mail address set out below. Our Websites and Social Media Our websites have links to other sites or services not provided by us, including social media websites that we may use along with you. These websites or services may have different privacy practices and policies than ours and we recommend that you review their privacy policies to determine if they are acceptable to you. While we are not responsible for those privacy policies and practices, we are responsible for any personal information we collect, use or disclose on those websites or services in accordance with this statement of privacy practices. Access, Correction, Inquiries and Complaints As required by applicable privacy legislation, we have appointed a Privacy Officer who is responsible for compliance with this policy.
For more information regarding our privacy policies and practices, please email our Privacy Officer at privacy@canfor.com, to the attention of the “Canfor Privacy Officer”.
You may also contact us in the same manner to request access to or to correct or delete any of your personal information held by Canfor or to make a complaint about our privacy practices. For other inquiries relating to this statement of privacy practices, you may also call us at 604-661-5241. Changes Canfor reserves the right to change this statement of privacy practices at any time by posting a new statement. Please check this page periodically for changes. Last Updated July 4, 2016
Our Company
Overview
Values
Canfor at a Glance
Leadership
Operations
Communities
Chetwynd, BC
Sustainable Forestry Initiative (SFI)
Search:
© 2020 Canfor | Contact Us | Site Map | Privacy Policy | Disclaimer | Web Developer Graphically Speaking
